TheChaosLegion
l want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
l will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
lf only our hearts could connect,
l could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and l know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
l'll be there for you.
l hope l can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
This way! Start chopping
the walls down here!
（宮仕え）
こっちだ！ ここから切り崩せ！
火の回りをここで止めるぞ！
We'll make our firebreak here
to keep the fire from spreading!
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（バルサ）ルイシャだね
Hey, that's a ruisha.
Take good care of that.
（バルサ）大切にとっておきな
The person you were as
Prince Chagum died tonight.
（バルサ）今夜で
皇子としての あなたは死んだ
From now on, you're going
to live as just Chagum.
これからは
ただのチャグムとして生きるんだ
私は 一度引き受けた仕事は
必ず全うする
Once l accept a job,
l see it through no matter what.
l'm not going to let you die.
絶対に あんたを
死なせたりはしない
That's what l was hired to do.
それが私の役目だからね
l know it will be difficult for you,
but bear with it and survive.
お前も つらいだろうが
それに耐えて生き延びるんだ
lf you do, one day you might
be reunited with your mother.
そうすれば いつか また
母君に会える日が来るかもしれない
Follow me.
ついておいで
Episode 2
Hunters,
Hunted
（ガカイ）
まだ消し止められておらんのか
They haven't managed
to put out the fire yet?
Master Gakai...
（シュガ）ガカイ様
This is the third time.
これで３度目になるな
チャグム皇子の命が
危険にさらされるのは
Three times, the prince's
life has been threatened.
So they still haven't
determined if he survived?
で いまだ ご無事かは
確認されておらんのか？
No.
はい
（ガカイ）時に シュガ
lncidentally, Shuga...
チャグム皇子に―
These rumors of Prince Chagum
being possessed, are they true?
つきものが ついておったという
ウワサは まことか？
As tutor-governor
of lchinomiya Palace...
私は 一ノ宮(いちのみや)のカシヅキとして―
...l like to think that l know
everything about Prince Sagum.
サグム皇子に関わる全てを
把握しているつもりだが
まあ よい
Well, no matter.
仮に あの火災で―
Even assuming that Prince Chagum
has, in fact, perished in this fire...
チャグム皇子が亡くなられるような
ことになったとしても―
...perhaps it is for the best.
それは それで
よきことなのかもしれん
万が一―
lf the unthinkable happened and
these unpleasant rumors had spread...
よからぬウワサが
広まるようなことになれば―
...it might have greatly hampered
the government's ability to function.
政(まつりごと)に大きな支障を
きたしておったであろうからな
これより精進に戻ります
lf you will excuse me,
l will return to my devotions.
Come on, l'll carry you piggyback.
You're asleep on your feet.
（バルサ）ほら おぶってやろう
寝ながら歩いてるじゃないか
どうした？ 早くおぶさりな
What's the matter? Hop on.
What does this "piggyback" mean?
おぶさるとは どういうことじゃ？
（バルサ）おぶさるってのは
背負われることだよ
Piggyback means being
carried on someone's back.
Commoner children...
平民の子はね
赤ん坊のときから―
...are carried on the backs of their
mothers from the day they're born.
おっかさんの背中に
おぶわれているもんなんだ
恥ずかしいことでも
なんでもないんだよ
There's no shame in being carried.
Everyone grows up doing it.
みんな そうやって
大きくなるんだから さあ
Hop on.
lt's warmer and more comfortable
for you this way, isn't it?
こうすりゃ温かいし楽だろ？
（チャグム）うん
（バルサ）そのまま眠っちまいな
Go on and get some sleep.
lt is Shuga.
（シュガ）シュガにございます
聖導師(せいどうし)様に お目通りを
お願いしたく参りました
l have come to ask for an audience
with the master star reader.
Why have you come?
（聖導師）何用だ？
l already know about Ninomiya Palace.
二ノ宮(にのみや)の件なら
すでに耳に入っておる
（シュガ）聖導師様
Master Star Reader...
お世継ぎであるサグム皇子が
決して健やかとは言えぬ今―
Prince Sagum, the heir to the throne,
is not in the best of health.
One would think that Prince Chagum
would be vital to us now.
チャグム皇子は我々にとって
大切な御仁のはず
What, exactly, are you implying?
何を申したいのだ？
これより 無人の体(てい)にて！
The remainder of this conversation
will take place before empty vessels.
lf l may...
恐れながら 帝(みかど)は―
l believe His Majesty ordered
the death of Prince Chagum.
チャグム皇子を亡き者にせよとの
命をお下しになられたはず
亡き者？
His death?
（シュガ）私の杞憂(きゆう)であれと
祈っておりました
l prayed that
l was worrying needlessly.
ですが もはや そうは思えません
But l can no longer fool myself.
His Highness began to meet with
strange accidents one after another...
私が 皇子のご様子を―
聖導師様に
報告申し上げた直後から―
立て続けに あのような…
...immediately after l reported
his condition to you.
The prince is
descended from the gods.
神の子孫である皇子に―
つきものがつく などということは
断じてあってはならぬ
He cannot be possessed by
evil spirits under any circumstances.
Regardless of whether he was ever,
in fact, truly possessed.
それが事実であろうと
なかろうとな
But was there truly nothing
that could have been done for him?
しかし 本当に打つ手は
なかったのでございましょうか？
Do not speak so glibly.
たやすく申すな！
二ノ妃(にのきさき)が 市井の呪術師に
送った文を忘れたか？
Have you forgotten the message that
the second queen sent to that...
...common magic weaver?
全てはカシヅキである
そなたが先走った結果
This is due to your hasty, reckless
actions as his tutor-governor.
だが こよいの火災にかぎり―
However, unlike the earlier
incidents, the fire tonight...
帝の命によるものではない
...was not set on
the orders of His Majesty.
シュガよ
Shuga...
星の相と政にしか
目を配らずにおると―
...if you focus too long on
the workings of politics and the stars...
人の心というものに
頓着せぬようになってしまうのう
...you will soon lose sight of
the workings of the human heart.
わしは 二ノ妃殿が
母であるということを忘れておった
l had forgotten that
the second queen is also a mother.
l am told that she summoned
to Ninomiya Palace last night...
昨夜は
皇子を救ったという女用心棒を―
...a female bodyguard who
had saved the life of the prince.
二ノ宮に呼び寄せたと聞く
Deducing that
her son was in danger...
わが子の危険を察した二ノ妃が―
...she likely used this bodyguard
to allow the prince to escape.
その女用心棒を使って
皇子を逃がしたのであろう
火災は そのための目くらまし
The fire is merely a ploy
to cover their tracks.
l doubt that you will find his body.
恐らく ご遺体は見つかるまい
Then Prince Chagum is still...
ではチャグム皇子は…
（聖導師）うむ
だが このことは他言無用
But you are to speak of this to no one.
A significant number have heard
this rumor of a possessing spirit.
つきもののウワサを
耳にした者も少なくない今―
lf Prince Chagum is believed
to have died in the fire...
チャグム皇子が
業火に焼かれたとなれば―
...it will be convenient
for all concerned.
全てにおいて都合がいい
時に お前は―
lncidentally, how do you believe
the prince managed to escape...
なぜ皇子が 度重なる水難を
ああも簡単に逃れえたと考える？
...all of those drowning
attempts so easily?
ln my humble opinion, l believe that
the evil spirit possessing him...
恐れながら
皇子についたものとは―
...is in all likelihood a water demon.
水妖(すいよう)ではなかったかと
考えております
（聖導師）
水妖とは あの水妖のことか？
By "water demon," do you
mean that water demon?
Yes.
（シュガ）はい
わが新ヨゴ皇国の
「建国正史(けんこくせいし)」に記されている―
The water demon depicted in
The Official History of Shin-Yogo...
水の魔物にございます
...the chronicle of
Shin-Yogo's creation.
Shuga.
（聖導師）シュガよ
l have always greatly
valued your ability.
私は以前より
お前の才能を高く評価してきた
For that reason,
l feel that l must warn you.
それ故に忠告しておくが―
これから先
政の裏側に関われば―
Should you go on involving yourself
in the government's dark side...
もはや後戻りできぬ道に
足を踏み入れることになる
...you will be going down
a path of no return.
そなたが
思いもしなかったであろう―
A dark, sinister underbelly
to the star palace...
...whose existence you
most likely never suspected.
星ノ宮(ほしのみや)の
暗くおぞましい裏の世界にな
l have always been taught
that the world is composed...
光と闇 ２つが相まって この世を
形づくると教わってまいりました
...of light and darkness
in equal measure.
いかに暗く
曲がりくねった道であれ―
No matter how dark and twisted
the path may be, if it leads to heaven...
それが 天に通じているならば
私は 歩いて参る所存にございます
...then l should like to walk down it.
As you wish.
（聖導師）よかろう これから先―
Let that be the one and only
light to illuminate your path.
その思いが そなたの道を照らす
ただひとつの光となろう
ついてまいれ
Come with me.
わしは 帝のお許しを得て―
With His Majesty's consent,
l have decided to dispatch pursuers.
追っ手を出すことに決めた
皇子の御身を取り戻すためだ
To bring back the prince.
（シュガ）その真意は？
To what end?
（聖導師）うむ
先ほどの問いだがな
お前の言うとおり―
Going back to my question earlier...
...it is most likely a water demon
that has possessed the prince.
チャグム皇子についたものは
恐らく水妖であろう
That is why l intended to use fire
to try to kill it in our third attempt.
それで わしは３度目は
火による成敗をと考えておった
The Official History tells us that at
a spring fed by the Aoyumi River...
ところがだ
建国正史の文面には―
...Torugaru, the first mikado of
the Shin-Yogo empire...
新ヨゴ皇国の
初代皇帝トルガルは―
...slew a water demon that
had possessed a Yakoo child.
青弓川(あおゆみがわ)のいずる泉にて ヤクー人の
幼子についた水妖を倒し―
Upon doing this,
he declared himself mikado...
神のご加護を受ける天使として
帝を名乗ったと記されている
...the son of heaven, one who
receives the blessings of the gods.
The child was possessed...
幼子についた…
そこから読み取れることは―
From this, we can deduce it is
impossible for anyone other than one...
水妖の命を
絶つことができるのは―
天のご加護を受けた者以外に
ありえないということだ
...who has received heaven's blessings
to take a water demon's life.
You don't mean...
それでは…
チャグム皇子の御身が
宮に戻りしだい―
Upon Prince Chagum's return...
トルガル帝のときより伝わる
星心ノ剣(せいしんのつるぎ)を用いて―
...the mikado himself will
slay it using Star's Heart...
帝 自らの手によって
成敗することとなる
...the blade passed down
from Torugaru's time.
But he cannot!
そんな！ それは あまりにも…
Surely that would be much too...
（聖導師）分かっておる！
You need not tell me!
帝は御簾(みす)の奥で泣いておられた
Behind the bamboo blinds,
His Majesty was weeping.
たとえ 政のためとはいえ―
Even if it is for the
good of the government...
わが子の命を
自らの刃で断たねばならぬのだ
...he must take the life of his own son.
その苦悩がどれほどのものか―
l am sure that you understand how
great the mikado's suffering must be.
そなたにも分からぬではあるまい
帝の陰に仕えし狩人たちだ！
These are the Hunters,
who serve the mikado in secret!
Their true identity is known
only by the mikado and myself.
その正体を知る者は
わしと帝しかおらぬ
And now, you will be the third to know!
そなたは
その正体を知る３人目の者となる
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Toya?
トーヤ… トーヤ いるかい？
Toya, are you there?
（トーヤ）あっ バルサねえさん！
Balsa!
シーッ！ 入ってもいいかい？
Can l come in?
（サヤ）バルサさん！
Balsa.
帰ってたんですね
So you're back in town?
lt's been a long time, Toya.
久しぶりだね トーヤ
サヤも起こしちまって すまないね
Sorry, Saya, l didn't mean
to wake you up too.
（サヤ）いいえ そろそろ
起きようとしていたところです
That's all right.
l was about to get up anyway.
Oh, l see.
（バルサ）そうかい
By the way, do you two
know where Torogai is now?
ところで あんたたち―
トロガイが
今どこにいるか知らないかい？
Sorry, l haven't heard anything
about her in town lately.
ここしばらく
街ではウワサを聞きませんね
（バルサ）そうか…
ならいいんだ 忘れておくれ
l see.
Never mind then. Forget l asked.
起きな チャグム
Wake up, Chagum!
（トーヤ）じゃ タンダとは
まだ会ってないんですか？
Then you haven't run into Tanda yet?
He's here in town?
あいつ 街に来てるのかい？
ええ そろそろ バルサねえさんが
帰ってくるころじゃないかって
Yes. He said he thought you would
be coming back any day now.
うん… そちらは？
Who's that?
目が覚めたかい？
Are you awake?
What did you do, kidnap
some nobleman's child?
どこかの貴族の子供でも
さらってきたんですか？
（バルサ）まさか
Hardly.
私は この子の用心棒を
頼まれたってわけさ
l've been hired as
this boy's bodyguard.
（トーヤ）ふーん
Please, have a seat.
どうぞ お座りください
Thanks.
ありがとうよ
さあ
Go ahead.
l can't go into details with you, though.
だけど詳しい事情は話せないんだ
すごく やっかいなことなんでね
lt's quite complicated.
トーヤ この金で いくつか
買い物をしてきてくれるかい？
Toya, will you use this money
to buy a few things for me?
Just name it. l'd do anything for you,
come hell or high water.
何でも言ってくれよ
俺は バルサねえさんの頼みなら
たとえ火の中 水の中なんだからさ
l'm glad to hear it.
頼もしいね
First of all, l need ten big sheets
of oiled paper to keep the rain out...
それじゃ まず 雨をしのぐための
大きな油紙10枚と―
...and a bear pelt warm enough
for sleeping on a snowy mountain.
雪山でも眠れそうな
熊の毛皮１枚
それから 10日分の干し肉と餅
l also need ten days' worth
of dried meat and rice cakes.
Also a set of clothes
that will fit the boy.
あとは この子の丈に合う着物だね
（トーヤ）
任せときな それで ほかには？
Just leave it to me.
ls there anything else?
最後に もう１つ
長旅に適した馬を１頭
One last thing.
A horse that can
handle a long journey.
A horse?
馬って… １万ルガル金貨！
This is a 10,000 lugal gold coin!
Will buying a horse on the spot,
even for 10,000 lugals, be trouble?
１万でも即金で
馬を買うってのは難しいかい？
Who do you think you're talking to?
誰に言ってんだい
Around here, l'm the most reliable
errand runner there is.
俺は この辺りでも―
“１番使える頼まれ屋”って
言われてんだぜ
（バルサ）足が痛むかい？
Do your legs hurt?
Here, rub this on the parts that hurt.
lt'll make them feel a little better.
ほら 痛い所にすり込んでおきな
少しは楽になるよ
自分でできるかい？
Can you do it yourself?
l know how to do it.
やり方ぐらい知ってる
That comes to twenty lugal.
（店主）合わせて20ルガルだな
Twenty? Oh, come on now...
（トーヤ）
20？ ちょっと待ってよ
こんくらいにならない？
How about this much?
Ten? Are you trying
to drive me out of business?
（店主）
10ルガル？ 商売にならねえよ
（トーヤ）何言ってんの
Oh, what're you talking about?
lt's spring already.
もう春なんだし―
lf you don't sell this bear pelt now,
it'll just sit here till winter.
熊皮なんて 今 売らなきゃ
春まで持て余しちゃうよ
うーん… 16
Sixteen.
（トーヤ）話が分かるねえ
You're a sensible man.
All right then.
（バルサ）それじゃ―
２人が戻るまで
横にならせてもらいな
Until those two get back, stay in bed.
Keep the straw mat pulled over you.
筵(むしろ)をかぶって眠っちまいな
lt's far better than catching a cold.
嫌でも
風邪をひくよりマシだからね
普通の人間が持てる代物じゃないね
Ordinary people certainly wouldn't
be walking around with this.
いつか時が来たら使わせてもらうよ
お妃様
lf the time comes,
l'll use these, Your Majesty.
Did you see that
commotion last night?
（男性）
おい見たか？ ゆうべの騒ぎ
（店員）ああ
方角からすると二ノ宮だろうな
Yes, judging from the direction,
it was at Ninomiya Palace.
（男性）
死人でも出てたら えらいこった
l have to say it'll be
something else if somebody died.
You know, a certain
someone who lives there...
（男性）
万が一 二ノ宮のどなたかが…
（店員）バカ！
めったなこと言うもんじゃねえよ
ldiot! Don't even joke about that!
真っ先に鍛冶屋に行かなかったのが
悔やまれるね
l'm going to regret not having gone
straight to the blacksmith's...
Wh-What in the world?
な… 何だ？
l'm in over my head here.
こりゃ 私の手には負えないね
But without Torogai's help, l cannot...
けど トロガイがいないとなると…
Chagum.
チャグム
Chagum!
おい チャグム！
Are you all right?
あんた 大丈夫かい？
l must have been acting
strangely once again.
（チャグム）余は また
おかしなことになっていたようじゃな
何か悪い夢でも見たかい？
Were you having
a nightmare or something?
（チャグム）覚えておらぬ
l do not remember.
ただ こうなると―
But whenever this happens,
l feel an overwhelming urge to survive.
どうしようもなく生きていたいと
そう感じるのじゃ
Didn't l tell you? l won't
let you die, no matter what.
言っただろ？ 私は絶対に
あんたを死なせたりしないって
（チャグム）そうではない
That's not what l mean.
This isn't the first time
l've experienced this.
この思いは
今に始まったことではない
Ever since l've been
possessed by whatever this is...
何かが 余に取りついたころから
訳もなく生きていたいと思うのじゃ
...l've felt a desire to survive,
and l don't know why.
You're throwing quite a lot
of money around, aren't you?
（モン）
派手に買い込んでいるようだな
And now a horse too.
（モン）その上に馬か
青霧(あおぎり)越えでもするつもりか？
Are you planning to cross the
Misty Blue Mountains or something?
How is that any of your business?
関係ねえだろ
諦めるのか
You're not going to buy it?
“旅装束の ほころびは―”
As they say, "A weak seam
in one's travelling clothes...
“旅にて穴になりにけり”と
言うがな
...will grow into a hole
while on the road."
Nobody asked you!
余計な お世話だよ！
Good, this will be plenty for us.
（バルサ）
ああ これだけあれば十分だよ
l'm glad. Also, take these.
よかった それから これを…
この店の お弁当は
おいしいんですよ
The shop where l bought these
makes delicious lunches.
（バルサ）
あんたたちは ホントに気が利くね
You two are really thoughtful!
Eat while we have the chance.
さあ 今のうちに食べて…
すいません！
l'm sorry. l got everything else,
but l'm still working on the horse!
全部そろったんですけど
馬だけが まだ…
By the way, are you planning to
cross the Misty Blue Mountains?
ところで バルサねえさん
青霧山脈
越えるつもりなんですか？
What makes you ask that?
何で そんなこと聞くんだい？
Well, some strange guy asked me
that while l was out shopping.
いや… 途中 変な男に
そんなこと聞かれたもんで
But no need to worry.
l managed to deflect his questions.
でも 心配はいりませんよ
うまく まいてやりましたから
機転が利くね
だけど 馬ならもういいよ
You think fast on your feet.
Don't worry about the horse anymore.
そろそろ
出発しなきゃならないからね
We're going to have to set out soon.
（バルサ）悪いけど あんたたちも
今すぐ荷物をまとめるんだ
l'm sorry, but you two need to
pack up your things right away too.
Balsa?
バルサねえさん…
万が一
ここを知られてたら困るからね
lf they find out about this place,
it'll mean trouble for you two.
This is to thank you
for all you've done.
（バルサ）
これは 世話になった お礼だよ
あっ… こんなに もらえないよ
We can't take this much!
Just take it.
（バルサ）いいから
l'm asking you to leave your home.
This is nowhere near enough.
家まで引き払わせちまうんだ
それでも足りないくらいさ
What? But l was the one who
couldn't come through for you...
（トーヤ）
そんな… 下手 打ったのは俺なのに
ただし 金貨は
来年まで使っちゃいけないよ
But you mustn't use
the coins until next year.
分かったね？
ls that clear?
すいません
l'm sorry...
Goodbye! Take care of yourselves!
じゃ 達者でな
Are your legs bothering you?
足が痛むかい？
Are you hungry?
（バルサ）腹は？
大丈夫じゃ
l am fine.
だてに
一国の皇子だったわけじゃないね
You weren't a prince
for nothing, were you?
You have grit.
気骨があるよ
（バルサ）やはり
馬が手に入らなかったのは厳しいね
Not having a horse is going
to make this a lot tougher...
（バルサ）二つ月？
A double moon...
どうりで…
That's why they...
マズいね
身を隠す所もないってのに
This isn't good. There's nowhere
for us to hide out here, either...
Chagum! Run!
チャグム 走れ！
走るんだよ！
Run, l said!
As l sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like l was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before l knew it.
lt was none other than you
who was there for me.
l keep wishing, "l want to be strong."
l stumble and hurt myself again.
But because l have you to believe in,
l can get back to my feet.
l simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
l call out to my precious loved one.
ls my voice reaching you?
ln this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
l'm certain l sensed the presence
of the one that l hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
Balsa battles the Hunters alone.
However, she is mortally
wounded by an enemy blade.
Next time, "Fight to the Death."
What does Balsa see...
Episode 3
Fight to the Death
as her consciousness slips away?